Jorge Muñoz

Email: jorgemf@gmail.com Personal web: https://jorgemf.github.io

Phone: (+34) 657 139 626 GitHub profile: https://github.com/jorgemf

Personal statement

I am a Deep Learning Researcher & Engineer. I started my career in Artificial Intelligence with my degree in Computer Science Engineering, which I graduated with first-class honors in 2006. I continued my education with a Ph.D. in Artificial Intelligence and an MBA. I have worked mostly with startups from San Francisco, London and Madrid. Only on remote roles since 2015.

I base my work methodology in 2 principles: keep learning and improve the processes. That is why I spend a lot of time reading and understanding the latest papers in Deep Learning and why I always try to automatize repetitive tasks and define clearly any process.

Education

October 2011 – November 2012 **MBA** Part-Time at EOI (Escuela de Organización Industrial) Management School. Funded by EOI (see awards and prizes below). International stay at UCF for a week.

October 2008 – October 2011 **Ph.D.** in **Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence**. Imitation learning in video games and development of believable non-players characters. I was the main author of several published **papers** in international congress about **computational intelligence** in games (CIG 2009, CIG 2010, UKCI 2010).

I won the botprize in 2010 (Turing Test for videogames) with a Conscious Machine cognitive architecture. An AAA videogame company was interested in the technology. I tried to create a company (Comaware) with this technology.

October 2007 – September 2008 **Master** in Computer Science and Information Technology. Specialization: **Artificial Intelligence**. University Carlos III of Madrid. Funded by the university. My thesis was about using Artificial Intelligence for step-by-step resolution of linear equations.

October 2001 – November 2006 **Computer Science Engineering** (5 years career). Specialization: Artificial Intelligence. I graduated with **first-class honors** and **the best bachelor's thesis**. University Carlos III of Madrid.

Experience

May 2018 – January 2020

Founder at Serendeepia (Madrid)

In Serendeepia Research we were a small group of experts in Machine Learning and Deep Learning who built custom solutions based on state of the art research in Artificial Intelligence. I was **CEO** and **CTO** of the company. I created a remote-first culture with a well defined methodology to manage the projects: scrum and kanban boards. I picked our tools based on the best industry standards: Github with gitflow workflow for code, Kubernetes as cluster with Jenkins for continuous integration and Polyaxon as the platform to run experiments. I grew the company from 3 to 7 people, I managed successful projects for Fortune 500 companies and I lead the development of B2C products with the latest advancements in Deep Learning.

January 2016 – August 2018 Remote Machine Learning Engineer/Researcher at Chute (San Francisco, CA, USA) (Acquired in August 2018).

Keywords: Deep Learning, CEO, CTO, TensorFlow, Scrum, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Polyaxon

I was the only engineer in charge of processing the data from social networks (Instagram, Twitter) in real-time to create valuable insights.

I migrated the simple single label image classification model in Caffe to a multilabel model in TensorFlow with TensorFlow Serving. The new model had more labels (+100) and a better precision and recall for every class (>90% accuracy for most of them). I also established a scientific procedure to measure the quality of the models.

I increased the competitive advantage of our product with 2 new features:

- An aesthetic model which was able to score the beautifulness of the images with a state of the art CNN model.
- A model to create a perceptual hash of images using their local and semantic information which was used to find similar images.

Keywords: TensorFlow, TensorFlow Serving, Python, Convolutional neural networks, Deep Learning

June 2017 – April 2018

Remote contractor as Machine Learning Researcher at Good Al Lab (San Jose, CA, USA).

I was in charge to create **Deep Learning** research projects that run in ClusterOne for promoting and testing the platform. For example:

https://medium.com/clusterone/personalized-medicine-redefining-cancer-treatment-with-deep-learning-f6c64a366fff

Keywords: Deep Learning Research, Machine Learning Platform

March 2013 – September 2017 **Android lead developer** in startups in **London** (Quipper, Shopcade) and as a **remote contractor** (Appgree).

I lead the development of several Android mobile apps, most of them with more than a million downloads. I also trained the teams who took on the development of the apps when I left.

Keywords: Team Lead, Android, Java, Kotlin

December 2010 – February 2013

Entrepreneur period. Startups and side projects with colleagues:

- Comaware: new technology based on **Machine Consciousness** to control virtual characters in video games and autonomous robots.
- Howmaths: Artificial Intelligence applied to math problems. An A* algorithms applied to solve math equation systems.
- A video game engine for Android developed from scratch as a side project to use Artificial Intelligence to control the non-player characters and procedural content generation.

Keywords: Entrepreneur, Marketing, Android, Video Games, Java, C++

Visiting research at "Center for Computer Games Research" IT University of Copenhagen

(Denmark), group of Artificial Intelligence in video games. I worked in a project of controlling characters in video games throw an eye tracking system and neural networks.

Keywords: Recurrent Neural Networks, C++

Research staff in training at University Carlos III of Madrid. I supervised several bachelor's thesis related with Artificial Intelligence and video games.

I was rated by the students as an exceptional teacher (2008).

Keywords: Neural Networks, Java, C++

December 2006
Software developer in Spain in several companies: GTD Ingeniería de Sistemas y Software;

Research & Publications

August 2007

Several **papers** in international conferences and **book chapters** (see http://scholar.google.es/citations? hl=es&user=aHsYF-0AAAAJ for more details).

Participation in scientific committee of international conferences (GECCO 2011, IADIS 2009).

Complete list of publications publications: https://jorgemf.github.io/publications.html

Secosol soluciones y domótica.

Awards and prizes

2011	Winner team of the Human-Like Bot contest.
	Winner project (Comaware) in the national contest for university entrepreneurs organized
	by EOI. Awarded with an MBA at EOI and a study trip to Silicon Valley.
	Winner team of the 5th contests of ideas for creating scientific and technological based
	companies of the University Carlos III of Madrid with the project Comaware . We won six
	months of incubation in the business incubator of University Carlos III of Madrid.
	monars of measurement are susmess measurement of onwersity carries in or mauria.
2010	Winner team of the 2K BotPrize 2010 international contest. The 2K BotPrize is an adaptation
	of the Turing test to video games. Monetary prize of a \$2,000 and a trip to 2K studios in
	Canberra, Australia.
	Winner of the Car Set-up Optimization competition (using TORCS as simulator). \$500 prize.
2008	Paralla de la desta como confronte de la desta de la dela dela dela dela dela dela de
	Rated by the students as an exceptional teacher, congratulated by the University Carlos III of
	Madrid
2006	Graduated with first-class honours and best bachelor's thesis . 2006
2006	Graduated with first-class nonours and best bachelor's thesis. 2006
2005	Scholarship for outstanding academic achievement in the course 2005-2006.
2003	Scholarship for outstanding academic achievement in the course 2005-2000.
1999 and 1998	Finalist in the third edition of the national "Spring Mathematics Contest" held at the
	University Complutense of Madrid.
	oniversity completense of Madrid.

Media Appearances

October 2010 "Killer Bots Are Getting Human". John Bohannon. Science. Vol 330. no. 6000. pp. 30-31.

Science.

http://science.sciencemag.org/content/330/6000/30.2

October 2010 "The Awakening of Conscious Bots: Inside the Mind of the 2K BotPrize 2010 Winner",

aigamedev.com.

http://aigamedev.com/open/articles/conscious-bot/

September 2010 "Unreal Tournament 2010: Narrowing the Gap between Human and Bot". Surfdaddy Orca. h+

magazine.

http://hplusmagazine.com/2010/09/10/unreal-tournament-2010-narrowing-gap-between-

human-and-bot/

September 2010 "Un equipo español queda en primer lugar del 2K BotPrize 2010" ("A Spanish team win the 2K

BotPrize 2010"). Lektu / Microsiervos. **lainformacion.com** http://www.lainformacion.com/ciencia-y-tecnologia/tecnologia-general/un-equipo-espanol-

queda-en-primer-lugar-del-2k-botprize-2010_eB2nYg5smd9hxIN2WnHWR1/

Talks

March 2011 Guest speaker in the VI Days of Imaginática 2011. University of Sevilla. "Conciencia Artificial en

Videojuegos: diseñando máquinas más humanas". ("Machine consciousness in video games:

designing more human-like machines").

Idioms

Spanish Native

English Advanced (6.3/10 Duolingo Profiency Exam, equivalent to 93/120 in TOELF, 6.8/9 in IELTS or C1

in CEFR)